Guide to the Rice University Faculty meeting minutes records, 1914-2005 UA 107
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Faculty meeting minute records
1914-2007
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 107
8 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
Minutes, agendas, and correspondence for general meetings of the Faculty at Rice University.
Historical Sketch
General Faculty meetings have been held since the beginning of Rice Institute. Their nature, however, has changed as the University grew in size and complexity. Originally, the entire Faculty, headed by the President of the Institute made all the academic and policy decisions. With a growing number of Faculty members this was no longer feasible and committees were formed to meet the changing needs of the University. Input from the general Faculty was directed to these committees and the committees, in turn, reported their findings to the general Faculty. Decision making also was channeled through committees, earlier through the Executive committee, and more recently through the University Council. The committee, rather than the individual Faculty member, now serves as the advisory body to the President.
Scope and Contents
The Faculty Meetings record group contains minutes, agenda, and exhibits supporting the minutes (i.e. committee reports, etc.) from 1913 - 2005. In some time periods these files also include correspondence related to faculty meetings, drafts of minutes, faculty notices, committee lists, etc. The files are arranged chronologically and a folder exists for each faculty meeting containing at least the minutes of that meeting and often supporting material. There are occasionally subject folders interfiled chronologically where the bulk of material warrants such a file.
Access Restrictions
This material is available for research by approval of the Head of Special Collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to the Woodson Research Center from the Secretary of the Faculty. Date(s) received: 1974; 1977; 1978; 1982; 1983; 1992; and 2010.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: 1914-2005, 93132
  - Early Committee Lists and Related Documents-Rice Institute, 93139 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Administration, 93140 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes March 27, 1914-April 9, 1921, 93138 (Box 1, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes May 5, 1921-June 23, 1945, 93137 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes March 2, 1946-April 21, 1955, 93136 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Faculty Notices January 1946-June 1949, 93134 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes June 2, 1955-April 2, 1965, 93135 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes June 4, 1965-May 21, 1971, 93133 (Box 5, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes Oct. 18, 1971-November 12,1974, 93131 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Elections to University Council & Faculty Council April 1973, 93128 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Results of Balloting for University Council & Faculty Council Oct. November 1973, March-April 1974, 93127 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Faculty Notices 1974-1975, 114217 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Commencement 1975, 93124 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Drafts of Minutes, Notes, and Correspondence 1975-76, 93121 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Faculty Appointments 1974-75, 93125 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes February 3, 1975-April 18, 1977, 93130 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Faculty Notices 1975-76, 93123 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Faculty Notices 1976-77, 93119 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Faculty Secretary Correspondence 1976-77, 93117 (Box 7, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes May 13, 1977-November 27, 1984, 93129 (Box 8, Folder -)
  - Faculty Notices 1978-83, 93118 (Box 8, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes January 21, 1985-March 18, 1994, 93126 (Box 9, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes April 12, 1994-November 7, 2001, 93120 (Box 10, Folder -)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes January 29, 2002 - September 7, 2005, 93116 (Box 11, Folder -)
- Series II: Audio Visual Recordings, 1985-2007; 114212
  - Audio visual recordings of Faculty Meetings ( 1 cassette tape and 12 VHS tapes), 1985-1995; 114213 (Box 12, Folder -)
  - Audio visual recordings of Faculty Meetings (14 VHS tapes), 1998-2000; 114214 (Box 13, Folder -)
  - Audio visual recordings of Faculty Meetings ( 7 cassette tapes and 11 VHS tapes), 2001-2003; 114215 (Box 14, Folder -)
  - Audio visual recordings of Faculty Meetings (14 cassette tapes and 11 VHS tapes), 2003-2005; 114216 (Box 15, Folder -)
- Series III: Digital Content
  - 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Rice faculty meeting minutes, 1998; Rice Engineering Amoco Summer Research Program annual report (Box 13)